Guide to the Millicent Todd Bingham Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Conservation of natural resources; Environmental protection; Geography; Literature -- History and criticism; Psychology, Industrial; Students; Universities and colleges -- United States; Women -- Education; Women -- United States; World War, 1914-1918 -- Personal narratives; Amherst (Mass.) -- Description and travel; Berlin (Germany) -- Description and travel; Europe -- Description and travel; Gaspé (Québec); Latin America; Maine -- Description and travel; Miami (Fla.); New Mexico -- Description and travel; Paris (France) -- Description and travel; Southeast Asia -- Description and travel; Soviet Union -- Description and travel; Diaries; Geographers; Anderson, Harriet; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949; Berryman, Clifford Kennedy, 1869-1949; Bingham, Millicent Todd, 1880-1968; Bingham, Walter Van Dyke, 1880-1952; Brand, Katharine Edith; Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925; Cable, George Washington, 1844-1925; Canby, Henry Seidel, 1878-1961; Carson, Rachel, 1907-1964; Ciardi, John, 1916-1986; Commager, Henry Steele, 1902-1998; De Voto, Bernard, 1897-1955; Dickinson, Emily, 1830-1886; Ferguson, Leonard; Flanders, Ralph E. (Ralph Edward), 1880-1970; Freeman, Dorothy; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963; Gillies, Florence; Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey, 1875-1966; Harding, Walter, 1917-1996; Herrick, Phillip; Howe, Julia Ward, 1819-1910; Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920; Hunt, Norman; James, Ellen S. Curtiss; Kohn, John S. Van E.; Loomis, Eben Jenks, 1828-1912; Loomis, Elisha S. (Elisha Scott), 1852-1940; Loomis, George C.; Loomis, George; Loomis, Harriet E. B.; Loomis, Katherine; Loomis, Mary Alden Wilder, 1831-1910; Loomis, Sarah E.; Loṕez Aldana, Fernando, Pres. of Peru, 1784-1841; Lowell, Amy, 1874-1925; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982; Marquand, John P. (John Phillips), 1893-1960; Marsh, Othniel Charles, 1831-1899; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978; Milinowski, Marta, 1885-1970; Monnier, Mathilde; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; Munson, Marguerite; Noble, Mabel Stearns; Palmer, Alice Freeman, 1855-1902; Palmer, Frederick, 1873-1958; Palmer, George Herbert, 1842-1933; Palmer, Helen; Palmer, Mary; Perkins, Frances, 1880-1965; Pezet, Alfonso Washington, 1889-; Pezet, Federico Alfonso, 1859-1929; Plimpton, Calvin Hastings, 1918-; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Ruihley, Glenn Richard; Russell, Ada, 1879-; Sawyer, Elizabeth C.; Semple, Ellen Churchill, 1863-1932; Smith, Margaret Chase, 1897-1995; Stearns, Alfred E. (Alfred Ernest), 1871-1949; Stearns, Arthur French, 1864-; Stearns, Mary, Mrs., 1821-1901; Thomas, Joe C.; Todd, David P. (David Peck), 1855-1939; Todd, Mabel Loomis, 1856-1932; Todd, Rhoda Peck; Toynbee, Arnold, 1889-1975; Udall, Stewart L., 1920-2010; Van Doren, Carl, 1885-1950; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972; Ward, Lydia Avery Coonley, 1845-1924; Ward, Robert DeCourcy, 1867-1931; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905-1989; Watson, John B. (John Broadus), 1878-1958; White, William Allen, 1868-1944; Whitman, Charles S., 1868-1947; Wickersham, George W. (George Woodward), 1858-1936; Wilbur, Richard, 1921-2017; Willard, Mabel Caldwell; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928; Wright, Helen, 1914-1997; Yerkes, Robert M. (Robert Mearns), 1876-1956; Young, Stark, 1881-1963; Harvard University; Society of Woman Geographers; Vassar College
- Correspondence, 1884-1968; Series I; 19 linear feet (45 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Select Correspondence and Family Correspondence are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Letters from Millicent Todd Bingham are filed by recipient in the same alphabetical sequence as letters received. Under each name, letters are filed chronologically.
  General Correspondence is arranged chronologically. Letters with approximate dates or no dates are at the end of the chronological sequence.
  - Select Correspondence
    - Aldana, F. Lopez, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, Harriet
      - 1909-1935, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-9)
      - Journal-letters, 1911-1912 (Box 1, Folder 10-15)
      - Drafts of letters from MTB, 1911-1912 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Angell, James R., 1930 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Berryman, C. K., 1948 December 16 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Brand, Katherine E., 1957-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bryan, William Jennings, 1925 April 8 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Cable, George Washington, 1896 June 27 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1930 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Carson, Rachel, 1953-1964 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Ciardi, John, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Commager, Henry Steele, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - De Voto, Bernard, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      General
      See also: box 82, folder 186
    - Ferguson, Leonard W., 1952-1968 (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
    - Flanders, Ralph E., 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Freeman, Dorothy, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Frost, Robert, 1954-1961, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - ________, Elinor (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Gillies, Florence, 1930-1936, undated (Box 2, Folder 32-35)
    - Grosvenor, Gilbert H., 1915-1965 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - ________, Helen Wright (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Harding, Walter, 1957-1965 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Herrick, Philip, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Howe, Julia Ward, 1907 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Howells, William Dean, 1890-1914 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Hunt, Norman, 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 41-42)
    - James, Ellen S.
      - 1907-1919 (Box 2, Folder 43-44)
      - Copies of letters from MTB, 1907-1908 (Box 3, Folder 45-46)
    - Kohn, John S. Van E., 1956-1968 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Lowell, Amy, 1923-1925 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1954-1968 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - ________, Ada (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Marquand, John, 1937-1946 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Marsh, O. C., undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Mead, Margaret, 1936 January 10 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Milinowski, Arthur, 1909-1952 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Milinowski, Harriet (Ransom), 1912 January 19 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Milinowski, Marga, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Milinowski, Marta
      - 1904-1913 (Box 3, Folder 56-64)
      - 1914-1962, no date (Box 4, Folder 65-72)
      - Journal-letters, 1906 August-1908 August (Box 4, Folder 73-76)
      - Journal-letters, 1908 September-1912 March (Box 5, Folder 77-82)
      - Journal-letters (from MTB), 1906 August-1907 August (Box 5, Folder 83-85)
    - Monnier, Mathilde, 1902-1946, undated (Box 6, Folder 86-91)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1952-1955 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Morrison, Kathleen [secretary for Robert Frost], 1959 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Munson, Marguerite, 1962-1968 (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - Noble, Mabel Stearns, 1906-1911 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - Palmer, Alice Freeman, 1897-1899 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - Palmer, Frederick, 1918-1951, undated (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - Palmer, George Herbert, 1902-1933 (Box 6, Folder 98-104)
    - Palmer, Helen (Mrs. Frederick), undated (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Palmer, Mary, 1918 November 27 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Perkins, Frances, 1931-1962 (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - Pezet, A. W., 1908 December 22 (Box 7, Folder 108)
    - Pezet, Frederico Alfonso, 1925 August 7 (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - Plimpton, Calvin, 1960-1968 (Box 7, Folder 110-111)
      See also: Series V, Emily Dickinson, Publication Correspondence
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Ruihley, Glenn R., 1957-1962 (Box 7, Folder 113)
    - Russell, Ada, 1925-1936 (Box 7, Folder 114)
    - Sawyer, Elizabeth C.
      - 1896-1901 Jun (Box 7, Folder 115-124)
      - 1901 Jul-1906 (Box 8, Folder 125-136)
      - 1907-1937 (Box 9, Folder 137-151)
      - 1938-1950 Mar, no date (Box 10, Folder 152-155)
    - Semple, Ellen Churchill, 1915-1917 (Box 10, Folder 156)
    - Smith, Margaret Chase, 1947-1960 (Box 10, Folder 157)
    - Stearns, Alfred E., 1909-1935 (Box 10, Folder 158)
    - Stearns, Arthur F., 1908-1914 (Box 10, Folder 159)
    - Thomas, Joe C., 1918-1921 (Box 10, Folder 160-164)
    - Toynbee, Arnold, 1965 March 21 (Box 10, Folder 165)
    - Udall, Stewart L., 1962 (Box 10, Folder 166)
    - Van Doren, Carl, 1948 April 15 (Box 10, Folder 167)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1957, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 168)
      See also: box 86, folder 296
    - Ward, Robert De Courey, 1917-1930 (Box 10, Folder 169)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1950 September 11 (Box 10, Folder 170)
    - Watson, John B., undated (Box 10, Folder 171)
    - White, William Allen, 1933 April 25 (Box 10, Folder 172)
    - Whitman, Charles, 1915, undated (Box 10, Folder 173)
    - ________, Olive (Box 10, Folder 173)
    - Wickersham, George W., 1921-1939, undated (Box 10, Folder 174-176)
    - ________, Mildred (Box 10, Folder 174-176)
    - Wilbur, Richard, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 177)
    - Willard, Mabel Caldwell, 1907 May 5 (Box 10, Folder 178)
    - Williams, Talcott, 1913-1957 (Box 10, Folder 179)
    - Wright, Helen, 1961-1967 (Box 10, Folder 180-181)
    - Yerkes, Robert M., 1941-1962 (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - ________, Ada W. (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - Young, Stark, 1915-1925 (Box 10, Folder 183)
  - Family Correspondence
    - Aschenbach, Marion (Loomis), 1936-1965 (Box 11, Folder 184)
    - Avery, Susan Look, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 185)
    - Bagg, Ernest N., 1898-1902 (Box 11, Folder 186)
    - ________, Winthrop, 1914 (Box 11, Folder 186)
    - Banker, Willis, 1917-1952 (Box 11, Folder 187)
    - ________, Mary (Box 11, Folder 187)
    - ________, Margaret (Box 11, Folder 187)
    - Bingham, Bianca, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 188)
    - Bingham, Lemuel R., 1903-1938 (Box 11, Folder 189-190)
    - ________, Mary E. (Box 11, Folder 190)
    - Bingham, Lewis, 1907-1960 (Box 11, Folder 191)
    - ________, Ella (Box 11, Folder 191)
    - Bingham, Walter VanDyke (Box 11, Folder 191)
    - _______, Millicent (Todd) (Box 11, Folder 191)
      - 1912-1920 (Box 11, Folder 192-195)
      - 1921-1926 Jun (Box 12, Folder 196-202)
      - 1926 Jul-1931 Aug (Box 13, Folder 203-212)
      - 1931 Sep-1934 (Box 14, Folder 213-220)
      - 1935-1941 (Box 15, Folder 221-229)
      - 1942-1951, no date (Box 16, Folder 230-238)
    - Bowdle, Bertha, 1937-1968 (Box 16, Folder 239)
    - Clarke, Howard, 1932-1936 (Box 16, Folder 240)
    - ________, Elinor (Box 16, Folder 240)
    - Compton, Naomi, 1886-1893 (Box 16, Folder 241)
    - Coonley, Howard, Lydia, Mary, Prentiss, and Sarah, 1890-1960 (Box 16, Folder 242)
    - Dean, Jean (Frazier), 1965-1968 (Box 16, Folder 243)
    - Frazier, Alice, Charles, Don and Ted, 1932-1956 (Box 16, Folder 244)
    - Frazier, Lewis and Irma
      - 1923-1955 (Box 16, Folder 245)
      - 1960-1968 (Box 17, Folder 246-247)
    - Gardner, Eugene K., 1940 (Box 17, Folder 248)
    - Gilluly, Jim, 1936-1966 (Box 17, Folder 249)
    - ________, Enid (Box 17, Folder 249)
    - Harnagel, George, 1942-1968 (Box 17, Folder 250)
    - ________, Alice (Box 17, Folder 250)
    - Hubbard, Betsy, 1950-1959 (Box 17, Folder 251)
    - Ingersoll, Ernest, 1900 (Box 17, Folder 252)
    - Kent, Mary (Wilder), 1922-1965 (Box 17, Folder 253)
    - ________, Virginia (Box 17, Folder 253)
    - Loomis, Eben Jenks and Mary Alden (Wilder)
      - 1884-1901 (Box 17, Folder 254-263)
      - 1902-1912, no date (Box 18, Folder 264-273)
    - Loomis, Elisha S., 1914 (Box 18, Folder 274)
    - ________, George, 1963-1968 (Box 18, Folder 274)
    - ________, George C., 1914 (Box 18, Folder 274)
    - ________, Harriet E. B., 1913-1914 (Box 18, Folder 274)
    - Loomis, Katherine, 1963-1968 (Box 18, Folder 274)
    - ________, Larah E., 1914 (Box 18, Folder 274)
    - Luccock, George and Emma, 1932-1957 (Box 18, Folder 275)
    - ________, Emory and Lois (Box 18, Folder 275)
    - ________, Jean (Box 18, Folder 275)
    - McGrew, Ada Loomis, 1914 (Box 18, Folder 276)
    - Quimby, Tom, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 277)
    - Robinson, Charles Bonnycastle, Jr., 1924-1945 (Box 18, Folder 278)
    - ________, Helen Avery (Box 18, Folder 278)
    - ________, Goldsborough (Box 18, Folder 278)
    - Schmitt, Georgia (Luccock), 1945-1968 (Box 18, Folder 279)
    - Schober, Carrie (Loomis), 1914-1939 (Box 18, Folder 280)
    - Sevcik, Albert E., 1951-1967 (Box 18, Folder 281)
    - Shanklin, Susanna, 1893-1896 (Box 18, Folder 282)
    - Sheip, Ella, 1940-1950 (Box 18, Folder 283)
    - Sherrard, McCluer, 1963-1968 (Box 19, Folder 284)
    - Stearns, Martha, undated (Box 19, Folder 285)
    - Stifler, Francis Carr, 1945-1965 (Box 19, Folder 286)
    - ________, Carol Jean (Box 19, Folder 286)
    - Stoddard, Ed, 1947-1952 (Box 19, Folder 287)
    - ________, Nancy (Box 19, Folder 287)
    - Todd, David Peck (Box 19, Folder 287)
    - _______, Mabel (Loomis)
      - 1884-1902 Aug (Box 19, Folder 288-304)
      - 1902 Sep-1910 May (Box 20, Folder 305-323)
      - 1910 Jun-1923 (Box 21, Folder 324-351)
      - 1924-1939 (Box 22, Folder 352-370)
    - Todd, Rhoda (Peck), 1894 (Box 22, Folder 371)
    - Tracy, William B., Jr., 1944-1958 (Box 22, Folder 372)
    - Wilder, Constance P., 1917-1949, undated (Box 22, Folder 373)
    - Wilder, Esther, 1902-1923 (Box 22, Folder 374)
    - ________, Herbert A. (Box 22, Folder 374)
    - Wilder, Mary (Jones), 1884-1893 (Box 22, Folder 375)
  - General Correspondence
    - 1885-1899 Jun (Box 23, Folder 376-392)
    - 1899 Jul-1903 Dec (Box 24, Folder 393-407)
    - 1904 Jan-1906 Oct (Box 25, Folder 408-420)
    - 1906 Nov-1909 Dec (Box 26, Folder 421-431)
    - 1910 Jan-1915 Aug (Box 27, Folder 432-443)
    - 1915 Sep-1918 Oct (Box 28, Folder 444-455)
    - 1918 Nov-1920 Dec (Box 29, Folder 456-467)
    - 1921 Jan-1925 Jun (Box 30, Folder 468-479)
    - 1925 Jul-1930 Dec (Box 31, Folder 480-492)
    - 1931 Jan-1935 May (Box 32, Folder 493-503)
    - 1935 Jun-1939 Jun (Box 33, Folder 504-514)
    - 1939 Jul-1943 Feb (Box 34, Folder 515-526)
    - 1943 Mar-1946 Jun (Box 35, Folder 527-539)
    - 1946 Jul-1950 Jun (Box 36, Folder 540-551)
    - 1950 Jul-1954 Dec (Box 37, Folder 552-566)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 38, Folder 567-578)
    - 1958 Jan-1960 Jun (Box 39, Folder 579-590)
    - 1960 Jul-1962 Mar (Box 40, Folder 591-601)
    - 1962 Apr-1964 Jul (Box 41, Folder 602-612)
    - 1964 Aug-1966 Sep (Box 42, Folder 613-622)
    - 1966 Oct-1968 Sep (Box 43, Folder 623-632)
    - 1968 Oct-Dec (Box 44, Folder 633)
    - no date [c. 1890-1899] (Box 44, Folder 634)
    - no date [c. 1910-1919] (Box 44, Folder 635)
    - no date [Pre-1920] (Box 44, Folder 636-640)
    - no date [c. 1920-1952] (Box 44, Folder 641-642)
    - no date [Post-1920] (Box 44, Folder 643-647)
    - no date [c. 1920-1929] (Box 44, Folder 648)
    - no date [c. 1940-1949] (Box 44, Folder 649)
    - no date [c. 1950-1959] (Box 45, Folder 650)
    - no date [c. 1960-1968] (Box 45, Folder 651)
    - no date (Box 45, Folder 652-655)
- Biographical Material, 1879-1968; Series II; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  This series is arranged by type of material, and chronologically within each category.
  For autobiographical sketches see: APPENDIX, Records and Tapes, Items 10-13.
  - Biographical sketches
    - Printed and TMs (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1923-1961 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Genealogy
    - Documents and notes (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1932-1968 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Certificates, with correspondence, 1898-1957 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Reminiscences
    - 1887-1927, 1933-1938, 1943-1964, undated (Box 46, Folder 6-10)
    - Transcripts of taped interviews, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 11-12)
    - Transcript of taped interview with Richard B. Sewall, 1963 June 17 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Concerning Emily Dickinson, 1932-1959, undated (Box 47, Folder 14-17)
  - Notes for autobiography (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - "Millicent's Life," by Mabel Loomis Todd, 1879-1888 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Clippings about MTB, 1880-1957 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Newspapers re: Vassar commencement, 1902 June (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Notes about MTB, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Health
    - List of illnesses (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence with doctors
      - 1901-1959 (Box 47, Folder 24-28)
      - 1960-1968 (Box 48, Folder 29)
    - Writings by Walter VanDyke Bingham and doctors, 1925-1956 (Box 48, Folder 30)
    - "Strep" throat: correspondence, notes, charts, 1908 (Box 48, Folder 31)
    - Notes on visits to psychiatrist, 1927 (Box 48, Folder 32)
    - Car accident: correspondence, notes, 1928 (Box 48, Folder 33)
    - Pneumonia: sympathy letters, cards, notebook, 1937 (Box 48, Folder 34-35)
    - Journals of visits to psychiatrist, 1938-1952 (Box 48, Folder 36-37)
    - Prescriptions, bills, notes, 1903-1960 (Box 48, Folder 38)
    - Medical records, nurse's notes, 1966, 1968 (Box 48, Folder 39-40)
    - Notes by MTB and others on illness, 1966-1968 (Box 48, Folder 41)
  - Death and funeral: correspondence, obituaries, memorial book, 1968 December (Box 49, Folder 42)
  - General manuscripts and printed matter, undated (Box 49, Folder 43)
- Education and Teaching, 1885-1929; Series III; 7.5 linear feet (18 boxes)
  This series is organized chronologically by date of attendance at each school or college. Teaching is arranged chronologically by dates of teaching at each college.
  - Juvenilia
    - Writings (Box 50, Folder 1-3)
    - Notes by Millicent Todd (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Notebooks (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Letter to editor of St. Nicholas, 1889 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Artwork (Box 50, Folder 7-9)
    - Drawings, 1885-1895 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Sketchbooks (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Architectural drawings (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Handicrafts
      - 1886-1889 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - 1890 (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Notes and calling cards (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Invitations (Box 51, Folder 16-17)
    - Greeting cards (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Dance programs (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - Printed matter: religious organizations (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Theatres, museums, exhibits (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Travel souvenirs (Box 52, Folder 22-23)
    - Advertisement posters (Box 52, Folder 24)
  - Miss-Hill's School, Amherst
    - Math notebooks, 1888-1889 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Penmanship books, undated (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Maps: South America and Africa, undated (Box 52, Folder 27)
  - Boston Classical School
    - Notebooks, leaflet, 1889-1890 (Box 52, Folder 28)
  - Amherst College
    - Student newspapers, 1888-1891 (Box 52, Folder 29)
  - Mrs. Stearns School, Amherst
    - Compositions, 1891-1897 (Box 52, Folder 30-33)
    - French notebooks, 1892-1894, undated (Box 53, Folder 34)
    - American history notes, undated (Box 53, Folder 35)
    - Classical history notes (Box 53, Folder 35)
    - Notebooks: Reading, Exercises, Dictation, 1893-1894, undated (Box 53, Folder 36)
    - German notebooks, 1895-1897, undated (Box 53, Folder 37)
    - Old Testament history exercise book, 1896 (Box 53, Folder 38)
    - Report cards, 1893-1896 (Box 53, Folder 39)
    - Class notes and notes from friends, undated (Box 53, Folder 40)
    - Notes and jottings, undated (Box 53, Folder 41)
    - Concert programs, 1891-1896 (Box 53, Folder 42)
  - Miss Hersey's School, Boston
    - Annual circulars, 1895-1899 (Box 53, Folder 43)
    - Compositions, 1897 (Box 53, Folder 44)
    - Biology lab drawings, 1897-1898 (Box 53, Folder 45)
    - French notebook and lecture notes, 1898 (Box 53, Folder 46)
    - History notebook, 1897-1898 (Box 54, Folder 47)
    - Literature notebook, 1897-1898 (Box 54, Folder 48-49)
    - Loose notes and drafts, undated (Box 54, Folder 50)
  - Vassar College
    - Academic transcript, 1902 (Box 54, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence, 1900-1902 (Box 54)
    - Anthropometric records, 1902 (Box 54)
    - Class schedules, 1898-1902 (Box 54, Folder 52)
    - Essays, 1901-1902, undated (Box 54, Folder 53-55)
    - Astronomy notes, undated (Box 54, Folder 56)
    - Biology notebooks, 1900 (Box 54, Folder 57-58)
    - Biology lab: outlines, drawings, notes, 1901-1902 (Box 55, Folder 59-62)
    - Biology/Psychology notebook, 1902 (Box 55, Folder 63)
    - Debate notebook, undated (Box 55, Folder 64)
    - Economics notes, 1900-1901, undated (Box 55, Folder 65-66)
    - English notebook and notes, 1901-1902 (Box 55, Folder 67-68)
    - English notebooks, undated (Box 56, Folder 69-70)
    - Ethics notebooks, 1901-1902 (Box 56, Folder 71)
    - French notebooks, undated (Box 56, Folder 72-75)
    - French exercises and notebooks, undated (Box 57, Folder 76)
    - Geology notebook, 1901-1902 (Box 57, Folder 77)
    - Geometry notebook, 1898 (Box 57, Folder 78)
    - History notebooks, undated (Box 57, Folder 79-81)
    - Hygiene notebook, undated (Box 58, Folder 82)
    - Latin translation notebook, undated (Box 58, Folder 83)
    - Literature notebook and notes, undated (Box 58, Folder 84)
    - Mineralogy notes, undated (Box 58, Folder 85)
    - Physics notebooks, 1899 (Box 58, Folder 86-87)
    - Physics lab notebooks, 1899-1900 (Box 58, Folder 88-89)
    - Psychology notes, 1901-1902 (Box 59, Folder 90)
    - Psychology notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 91)
    - Teacher preparation notes, 1902 (Box 59)
    - Loose notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 92)
    - Examinations, 1896-1900 (Box 59, Folder 93)
    - Personal notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 94-95)
    - Clubs and organizations (Box 59, Folder 96)
    - Clubs and organizations: Vassarion, 1902 (Box 59, Folder 97)
    - Song lyrics, cheers, poems, music (Box 59, Folder 98)
    - Poems collected by Millicent Todd (Box 59, Folder 99)
    - Lecture and debate programs (Box 59, Folder 100)
    - Concert programs (Box 59, Folder 101)
    - Play programs (Box 59, Folder 102)
    - Programs and Class Day book (Box 60, Folder 103)
    - Graduation Class Day, 1902 (Box 60, Folder 104)
    - Newspaper clippings and magazine articles (Box 60, Folder 105)
    - Annual catalogues, 1896-1902 (Box 60, Folder 106-107)
    - Summer course (not attended), 1902 (Box 60, Folder 108)
  - The Sorbonne, University of Paris
    - French colonial geography: lecture notes, 1905-1906 (Box 60, Folder 109-110)
    - French literature notebooks
      - 1905-1906 (Box 60, Folder 111)
      - 1905-1906 (Box 61, Folder 112-114)
    - History notebook of Marta Milinowski, used by Millicent Todd, 1905-1906 (Box 61, Folder 115)
    - Notes, tickets, program (Box 61, Folder 116)
    - Expense account (Box 61, Folder 117)
  - Private Tutor, Boston
    - Spanish notebooks; notes, receipts, 1907 (Box 61, Folder 118)
  - University of Berlin
    - Notebooks, 1909-1910 (Box 61, Folder 119)
    - Printed matter: newspapers and clippings (Box 61, Folder 120)
    - Expense account, 1909-1910 (Box 62, Folder 121)
    - Souvenirs (Box 62, Folder 122)
  - Mt. Holyoke College
    - Special courses in physiography: notes, 1915-1916 (Box 62, Folder 123)
  - Graduate Study
    - Correspondence and applications, 1916-1955 (Box 62, Folder 124)
  - Radcliffe College
    - "Peruvian Guano," master's thesis, 1917 (Box 62, Folder 125)
    - Commencement programs, 1923 June 20 (Box 62, Folder 126)
    - Report cards, 1915-1920 (Box 62, Folder 127)
    - Climatology lecture notes, 1916 (Box 62, Folder 128)
    - Economic geography notes, 1916 October (Box 62, Folder 129)
    - Geography notes, 1916-1917 (Box 62, Folder 130-131)
    - "Geography of the French Alps," notebook, 1917 (Box 62, Folder 132)
    - Geology notes, 1916-1920 (Box 62, Folder 133-135)
    - Historical geology lecture notes, Circa 1916 (Box 63, Folder 136)
    - Human geography lecture notes, 1917 (Box 63, Folder 137)
    - Meteorology notes, 1916 (Box 63, Folder 138-140)
    - Modern American literature notes, 1923 (Box 63, Folder 141)
    - Politics notes, 1924 (Box 63, Folder 142)
    - Urban geography lecture notes, undated (Box 63, Folder 143)
  - Harvard University
    - Correspondence re: conferring of Ph.D. degree, 1917-1923 (Box 63, Folder 144)
    - Anthropology notes, 1916 (Box 63, Folder 145)
    - Geography